Support for NPR music comes from Capital
One, proud supporters of NPR music and
the Tiny Desk Contest. What's in your
wallet? Learn more at capitalone.com.
She [music] was standing at the front
[singing] door
when I came home last night.
Good book here in her left hand
and a rolling pin in her right.
She said, "You come home for the last
[music and singing] time with a whiskey
on your breath.
You don't listen to my preaching, boy.
I'm going to have to beat you half to
death."
Give me just one [music] more last
chance before you say we're through.
I know I drive [music and singing] you
crazy, baby. It's the best that I can
do.
We're just some good old
>> [music]
>> boys
>> [singing]
>> making noise. We ain't running around on
Give me just [music] one [singing] more
last chance before you say we're
through.
First, she hit my glasses cuz she knows
that I can't see.
She said, "You ain't going nowhere,
[music] boy, [singing] till you spend a
little time with me."
When the boys called [music] from the
honky-tonk, there's a party going on
down [singing] here. Well, she might
have took my car keys, but she forgot
[music] about my old John Deere.
Give me just one more
[music and singing] last chance before
you say we're through.
I know I drive you crazy, baby. It's
[music] the best that I can do.
We're just some good old boys
making noise. We ain't running [singing]
around on [music] you.
Give it just one more last chance before
you say we're through.
>> [music]
>> Give it just one [singing] more [music]
last chance before you say we're
through.
I know I drive you crazy, baby. It's
[music] the best that I can do.
We're just some good old boys who make
[music and singing] noise. We running
around on you.
Give it just one more last chance before
you say we're through.
Give it just [music] one more last
[singing] chance before you say we're
through.
Oh, yeah.
One more last [music] chance.
It's all I need.
>> [applause]
[applause]
>> Thank you very much.
Very kind.
Yep. Whenever you're ready, boys.
It's a song I wrote about my wife, Amy
[music] Grant's smile, first time I ever
saw her.
>> [music]
>> Face of [singing] an angel
pretty eyes
that [music] shine.
I lie awake at night
>> [music]
>> wishing [singing] you were mine.
>> I'm standing here holding
the biggest heartache in town.
>> [music]
>> Whenever [singing] you come
oh, I
get weak [music and singing] in the
knees
and I lose my breath.
Oh, I try to [music and singing] speak,
but words won't come.
I'm so scared to death.
When you
smile that smile
the world turns [singing]
>> [music]
>> Whenever you come [singing]
>> I feel so helpless
I feel [music] just like a kid.
What is it about you that makes me keep
my feelings hid?
>> [music]
>> I wish I could tell you
but the words can't be felt.
Whenever [music and singing] you come
>> [music]
>> oh, I
get weak [singing] the knees
and I lose my breath.
Oh, [music and singing] I try to speak,
the words won't come. I'm so scared
[music] to death.
When you [singing] smile
that smile, [music]
the world turns
>> [singing]
>> upside down.
Whenever [music and singing] you come
around.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Oh,
I get weak in the knees [music]
and [singing]
I lose my breath.
>> [music]
>> Oh, I try to speak, the words won't
come. I'm so scared to death.
When you [singing] smile that smile,
>> [music]
>> the world turns
upside down.
Whenever you come around.
>> [singing]
>> When you smile that smile,
the world turns
upside down. [music and singing]
Whenever you [music] come around.
Whenever you [singing and music] come
around.
>> [music]
[applause]
>> Oh, thank you.
>> [applause]
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
What fun.
I think it's important to hear new songs
once in a while and I never stop writing
them.
So, we're going to do a couple new songs
for you that you hadn't heard yet.
>> [music]
>> Prisoners [music]
and paupers
outlaws [singing] and sharecroppers
all made [singing]
their way
>> [music]
>> to this town.
Singing [music and singing] about hard
times
Jesus and coal mines
turned my
whole world [singing and music]
upside down.
From [music] rags [singing]
to riches
some tough sons of
[music]
at the feet of
my [singing] heroes
I [music] learned.
They ran
wide [music and singing] open
could never
be broken
and I'll [music and singing] cross the
same bridges
they burned.
>> [music]
>> I just wanted [singing]
a seat
at the table. [music]
Maybe cause
>> [singing]
>> of a path [music] of
my own.
Sing all my sad [music and singing]
songs by heart and
till my [music and singing] heroes
are calling
me home.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Beer joints
and Bibles,
old tent [singing]
revivals,
that's where the music [music]
comes from. [singing]
With the sons and
the daughters
of our mothers [singing]
and fathers
who gave us
the courage [music and singing]
to run.
I just wanted
>> [singing]
>> to sit
at
the table. [music]
Maybe cause
>> [singing]
>> of a path of
my own.
Sing all
my sad [music and singing]
songs by heart and
till my [music] heroes
are calling
me home.
>> [music]
>> Sing [singing] all
my sad songs [music]
by heart and
till heroes
are calling [music]
me home.
>> [applause]
[cheering]
>> Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
>> [applause]
>> Uh this next song was inspired by me
seeing Arlington, the Arlington
Cemetery, for the first time many years
ago.
>> [music]
[music]
>> We sent [singing] our youngest off
[music] to war,
not sure what he was fighting for.
And one [singing] night they showed up
at our door
with a purple [music and singing] heart
and nothing more.
We're broken like [singing and music]
we've never been.
Ain't no medal [singing and music] going
to bring him back again.
What saddens [singing] me is no one
[music] wins.
Pride's [singing] the deadliest of sins.
I don't think I'll ever understand
[music and singing]
how unkind we treat our fellow man.
We [music] loved [singing] that boy till
the bitter end.
We fly that [singing and music] flag to
remember him.
>> [music]
[music]
>> I don't think I'll
ever understand [singing]
>> [music]
>> how unkind [singing] we treat our fellow
man.
We loved [music and singing] that boy
till the bitter end.
We fly [music and singing] that flag to
remember him.
It's not my [singing] way to criticize,
[music]
but I've seen the [singing] tears in a
mama's eyes.
>> [music]
>> Well, life ain't fair, I realize,
[music]
what you sacrifice [singing]
when a soldier dies.
Well, life [music] ain't fair, I
realize, [singing]
what you sacrifice when a soldier
[music and singing] dies.
>> [applause]
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Let me do a little tuning.
And once again, a really heartfelt thank
you for getting to come here and sing
some songs for It's
You got a great show. You're really
lucky to have it and should be proud.
We're proud to be here.
>> [applause]
[music]
>> This song came from losing my brother 33
years ago.
>> [music]
[music]
>> I [music] know your life
on earth [music] was troubled.
And only you [music]
could know
the pain.
You weren't afraid
to face the devil.
You were [singing and music] no
stranger
to toil.
>> [music]
>> Oh, as
>> [singing]
>> I owned that mountain,
I sung your
>> [singing]
>> worth
>> [music]
>> on earth
is done.
Go to
>> [music and singing]
>> him
from Shilo.
>> [music]
>> The [singing] father
of the
land
and the son.
>> [music]
>> Oh, how [singing] we cried
the day you left us.
Gathered [singing] round
your grave
to me.
Wish I could [music and singing] see
the angels' faces
and hear
>> [singing]
[music]
>> their sweet voices
on that
>> [singing and music]
>> high holy
mountain.
Sing your
word
>> [music]
>> till
Earth is done.
Go to
Him
on the shouting
of [singing] Father [music] and Son.
Father and
Son.
>> [music]
[music]
>> You're safely [singing] home [music]
in the arms of Jesus.
>> [music]
>> Eternal life
my brother's found.
The day will [singing]
come
>> [music]
>> I know I'll see him
in that sacred place
on that holy ground.
On that
high holy
>> [music and singing]
[music]
[singing]
>> Amen.
>> [music]
>> Thanks for having us.
>> [applause]
[cheering]
>> THANK YOU.
>> [applause]
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. [cheering]
HELLO BOYS.
>> [applause]
>> THANK YOU EVERYBODY.
>> NOW WE GET the free cheese.
>> [cheering]
>> Time to get [applause] some free cheese.
Yes.
>> [cheering]
>> Thank you.
Thanks for watching. Support for NPR
Music comes from Rivian, makers of
all-electric adventure vehicles designed
with the planet and future generations
in mind.